Preliminary Inventory to the League of Red Cross Societies Miscellaneous records, 1919-1922
Hoover Institution Archives
League of Red Cross Societies Miscellaneous records,
1919-1922
28017
League of Red Cross Societies
2 manuscript boxes (0.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, telegrams, reports, and minutes of meetings, relating to the founding of the League of Red Cross Societies and to relief operations in Europe.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1928.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Appendix of Names
Allen, R. F., Major - ARC Aide to Deputy Commissioner to Europe
Apson, Stockton - Acting Secretary General LORCS
Atkins, Alfred - Chief Accountant LORCS
Balfour. M. C. - Public Health LORCS
Bartlett, E. O., Col. - ARC Commissioner for Italy
Bicknell, Ernest P., Col. - ARC Deputy Commissioner for Europe, 1921
Brown, Donald W. - Director of Organization LORCS
Bryson, Lyman, Maj. - ARC Acting Director, Junior Red Cross, LORCS
Centanini - ICRC, Public Information, Xth International Red Cross Conference
Clarke, Walter - Chief Division of Popular Health Instruction
Cutler, Otis H. - Acting Chairman LORCS (for Davison)
Davison, Henry P. - Chairman Bd. of of. LORCS
Drummond, Eric - Secty. Gen. League of Nations
Emerick, J. P., Capt. - LORCS (Finances)
Emerson, Kendall, Dr. - ARC Deputy Commissioner to Europe
Farrand, Livingston, Dr. - Chairman, Executive Committee, ARC
Fitzgerald, Alice - Director, Nursing Dept., LORCS
Henderson, David, Sir, Lt. Gen. - Director, LORCS
Hill, A. R. - Vice Chairman, Executive Committee, ARC
Hill, Dr. A. Ross - Vice Chairman Central Committee in charge of Foreign Operations, ARC
Hill, Sir Claude - Acting Director-General, LORCS
Keppel, F. F. - Director Foreign Operations
Kittredge, T. B.
Knox, Dr. J. H. M., Jr. - Medical Director, ARC
Lakeman, Curtis E. - Assistant to ARC, Commissioner for Europe
Mills, Nelson - Major Director Foreign Accounts, ARC
Olds, Colonel Robert E. - ARC Commissioner to Europe, 1919
Persons, W. Frank - Vice-Chairman; 1. Director of Administration, LORCS, 1919; 2. Executive Committee, ARC - Director of Development, LORCS
Rappard, Wm. E., Dr. - LORCS Secretary General
Rockwell, Foster - Business Manager, LORCS
Ryan, Edward W., Dr. - ARC Commissioner, Western Russia
Saulter, Ernest - Vice President, ICRC
Seidemann, H. P., Maj. - ARC Deputy Comptroller, Foreign Accounts
Sand, Rene, Dr. - Secretary General, LORCS, 1922
Stouch, C. P. - Secretary to H. P. Davison
Strong, R. P., Col. - General Medical Diretor, LORCS
Walling, W. G. - Vice-Chairman, ARC
Stanley, Arthur, Sir - Chairman, British Red Cross
Access Points
International relief.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Civilian relief.
Container List
- Advisory Committee (Box 1., Folder 1)
  - Letters
    - Davison to Bohney, 1921 August 30 (Death of Sir David Henderson; appointment of Sir Claude Hill and an Advisory Committee)
    - Davison to Bicknell, 1921 August 30 (Advisory Committee)
    - Bicknell to Farrand, 1921 September 22 (Bicknell's appointment as ARC representative to Advisory Committee)
    - Bicknell to Sand, 1921 September 22 (same)
    - Bicknell to Sir Claude Hill, 1921 September 23
    - Sautter to Sir Claude Hill, 1921 September 27 (LORCS headquarters)
    - Sir Claude Hill to Stanley, Farrand, Catier
      - 1921 October 12 (Conference in Washington, D.C.)
      - 1921 October 13 (Notes for Advisory Committee; proposed budget)
      - 1921 October 13 (Notes pour le Comite Conseil, French translation of the above note)
      - 1921 October 14 (Report on the results of preliminary inquires as to moving the headquarters of the LORCS)
    - Sir Claude Hill to Ador (LORCS headquarters)
    - Sir Claude Hill to Cheneviere, 1921 September 24 (LORCS headquarters)
- American Red Cross Headquarters, Washington, D.C. (Folder 2)
  - Cables
    - Henderson to Davison, 1919 June 14
    - Farrand to Davison, 1919 June 16
    - Farand to Davison, 1919 June 30
    - Morris to Davison, 1919 September 26 (Promotion of Sir David Henderson)
  - Letter - Walling to Olds, 1919 October 8 (Relationship of ARC to LORCS)
  - Cables
    - Bicknell to Farrand, 1919 October 21
    - Olds to Bicknell, 1919 October 24 (Withdrawal of Chesley from Poland)
- Articles of association, by-laws, etc. (Folder 3)
  - Proofs
    - Articles of association
    - Articles of association (final publication)
    - Draft of by-laws
  - Memorandum-1919 December 22 (LORCS - purpose, origin, etc., (p.7: "a general council has been called to meet at Geneva, 1920 March 2")
- Bicknell, Ernest P., Col., Commissioner for Europe (Folder 4)
  - Letter - Persons to Bicknell, 1919 June 24
  - Memorandum - Bicknell to Richardson, 1921 September 13 (Red Cross funds for scholarship to Latvian nurse)
  - Letters
    - A. R. Hill to Bicknell, 1921 (same)
    - Bicknell to A. R. Hill, 1921 October 21 (ARC appropriations to be expended in Poland and handed to LORCS)
    - Bicknell to Mills, 1921 October 24 (Red Cross funds for scholarship to Latvian nurse)
    - Waters to Meek, 1921 November 5 (same)
    - Olmsted to Mills, 1921 November 11 (Red Cross funds for scholarship to Latvian nurse)
    - Mills to A. R. Hill, 1921 November 15 (same)
    - Mills to Fletcher, 1921 November 17 (same)
    - A. R. Hill to Bicknell, 1921 November 18
    - Hodges to Bicknell, 1921 January 25
    - Bryson to Bicknell, 1921 February 2 (Publications on typhus in Cattaro)
    - Bicknell to Bryson, 1921 February 8 (same)
    - Sand to Bicknell, 1922 February 23 (Liquidation of various ARC Commissions)
    - Bicknell to Sand, 1922 February 25 (same)
    - Sand to Bicknell, 1922 March 1 (New York Times quote: ".. .Red Cross League may face collapse.. .")
    - Rowe to Bicknell, 1922 April 1 (Second Council Meeting: proposal for Pan-American Conference)
    - Bicknell to Sir Claude Hill, 1922 April 11 (Pan-Am Union, Pan-Am. Conference)
    - Bicknell to Rowe, 1922 April 11 (Proposed Pan-Am. Conference)
    - Kenny to Bicknell, 1922 April 21 (same)
    - Bicknell to Kenny, 1922 April 25 (Proposal for Pan-American Conference to be held in Washington)
    - Kenny to Bicknell, 1922 April 28 (same)
    - Bicknell to A. R. Hill, 1922 June 2 (Attitude of French government toward LORCS)
    - Sir Claude Hill to Bicknell, 1922 June 10 (Miss Olmsted to discuss 3rd International Course for Public Health Nurses)
  - Memorandum - Bicknell to A. R. Hill, 1922 June 12 (Sir Claude Hill on moving of headquarters to Paris)
  - Letters
    - Bicknell to Sir Claude Hill, 1922 June 14 (Miss Nelson's attendance at Conference of Nurses)
    - Sir Claude Hill to Bicknell, 1922 June 19 (same)
  - Cable - Bicknell to (?) Hill, 1922 June 24 ("French Government has taken action necessary enable Licross come Paris")
- British Red Cross Society (Folder 5)
  - Memorandum-1921 March 8 (H. S. Wells on attitudes of British, French and American Red Cross pertaining to Geneva Conference)
  - Letters
    - Lakeman to Stanley, 1921 March 10 (Geneva Conference)
    - Lakeman to Henderson, 1921 March 10 (same)
    - Stanley to Lakeman, 1921 March 12 (same)
- Bryson, Lyman, Division of Junior Red Cross (Folder 6)
  - Letters
    - Bryson to Persons, 1919 October 2 (Program of JRC in Europe)
    - Persons to Bryson, 1919 October 10
    - Persons to Bryson, 1919 November 14 (Program of JRC in Europe)
    - Bryson to Persons, 1919 November 18
    - Persons to Bryson, 1919 November 22
    - Bryson to Persons, 1919 December 6
    - Persons to Bryson, 1919 December 19
    - Bryson to Bicknell, 1921 August 25 (Funding: Nansen, Ador, Briand)
    - Bicknell to Bryson, 1921 August 29 (Russian famine relief)
- Bulgarian Red Cross (Folder 7)
  - Memorandum - Kittredge to Department of Organization, LORCS, 1921 March 21 (Peace program and attitude toward LORCS)
- Cannes Conference, 1919 (Folder 8)
  - Cables, 1919
    - March 20 (Incoming cable. Cannes Conference)
    - March 20 (same)
    - March 21 (same)
    - March 21 (same)
    - March 21 (same)
    - March 21 (same)
    - March 24 (same)
    - April 1 (same)
    - April 3 (same)
    - April 3 (same)
    - April 4 (same)
    - April 4 (same)
    - April 4 (same)
    - April 5 (same)
    - April 7 (same)
    - April 7 (same)
    - April 7 (same)
    - April 8 (same)
    - April 8 (same)
    - April 8 (same)
    - April 8 (same)
    - April 8 (same)
    - April 11 (same)
    - April 14 (same)
    - April 14 (same)
    - April 14 (same)
    - April 14 (same)
    - April 14 (same)
    - April 14 (same)
    - April 14 (same)
    - April 15 (same)
    - March 31 (Outgoing cable, Cannes Conference)
    - April 1 (same)
    - April 1 (same)
    - April 2 (same)
    - April 3 (same)
    - April 3 (same)
    - April 4 (same)
    - April 9 (same)
    - April 12 (same)
  - Newsclipping-1919 March 26 (Experts who will confer at Cannes)
  - Memoranda
    - Bicknell to Strong, 1919 June 18 (Arrival of dr. Janiszewski)
    - Emerick to Olds, 1919 August 22 (Charges against LORCS appropriation WO-13)
  - Cables
    - Henderson to Morris, 1921 March 31 (IRC Conference)
    - Centanini to Morris, 1921
      - April 1 (same)
      - April 2 (same)
      - April 4 (IRC Exhibition)
      - April 4 (Xth IRC Conference)
      - April 6 (same)
      - April 7 (same)
      - April 8 (same)
      - April 11 ("Save the Children Fund" - International Congress)
- Clarke, Walter. Report, "Field Work in Germany, Denmark, Sweden, Norway... ", 1920 October 9. Letter - Clarke to Burnham, 1922 April 11 (letter of resignation) (Folder 9)
- Conference minutes (Folder 10)
  - Relationship of ARC to LORCS
  - 1919
    - May 28 (conference minutes)
    - June 13 (same)
    - August 6 (same)
    - August 12 (same)
    - August 27 (same)
    - October 25 (same)
    - October 27 (same)
    - December 30 (same)
  - 1920
    - March 24 (same)
    - April 19 (same)
    - April 28 (same)
- Cross index folder (Folder 11)
- Donations of materials by the American Red Cross to LORCS, 1919 (Folder 12)
  - Letters, Bridges to Payson
    - 1919 October 30 (Total costs of appropriations. With attachment: letter, October 27 to Lewis from Bridges)
    - October (Price Advice Sheets from ARC to LORCS)
- Finances, Miscellaneous, 1919 (Folder 13)
  - Letters
    - Seidemann to Stouch, 1919 March 19 (Stouch's accounts)
    - Hunter to Cutler, 1919 May 28 (Italian Commission - "Red Cross Tuberculosis Commission")
    - Memorandum, Campbell to Seidemann, 1919 June 5
    - Campbell to Roberts, 1919 June 14 (Comptrollership of League)
    - Campbell to Lilly, 1919 June 21
    - Seidemann to Lilly, 1919 June 23
  - Cable - Rockwell to Cutler, 1919 June 26 (Selling of American dollars)
  - Letter - Seidemann to Davison, 1919 June 18 (Appropriation of WO-13. Attachments all concerned with WO-13)
  - Memoranda
    - Seidemann to Cutler, 1919 June 27 (Status of appropriation WO-13)
    - Hunter to Olds, 1919 June 30 (Appropriation WO-13. Attachments all concerned with WO-13. Summary of appropriation WO-13)
  - Letter - Mills to Seidemann, 1919 June 26
  - Memorandum - LORCS to All Dept. Heads, 1919 July 1 (Approval of vouchers)
  - Letters
    - LORCS to Seidemann, 1919 July 9
    - Rockwell to Seidemann, 1919 July 11 (Allowances)
    - Rockwell to Seidemann, 1919 August 7
    - Seidemann to Rockwell, 1919 August 19
    - Seidemann to Roberts, 1919 August 20 (Expenses)
  - Memoranda
    - Seidemann to Assistant Secretary General, 1919 August 29 (Appropriation system)
    - Seidemann to Comptroller, 1919 August 29 (Outline for handling cash)
    - Secretary General to Heads of Deps., 1919 September 1 (Payrolls and personnel records)
    - Seidemann to Henderson, 1919 September 2 (Distribution of general orders)
    - Seidemann to Henderson, 1919 September 8
  - Letter - Grove to Seidemann, 1919 October 2
- Financial matters - Nelson Mills (Folder 14)
  - Cable - Farrand to Mills, 1920 February 2
  - Letter - Mills to Lewis, 1920 February 5
  - Cable - Olds to Lewis, 1920 February 6
  - Memoranda
    - Mills, 1920 February 27
    - Bobbett to Mills, 1920 March 11
    - Mills, 1920 April 12 (Memorandum for Staff conference re Roberts)
  - Cables
    - Rae to Mills, 1920 April 27
    - Rae, Farrand to Mills, 1920 May 27
  - Memoranda
    - Gee to Mills, 1920 May 29
    - Mills to Gee, 1920 May 29
  - Letters
    - Gee to Marjes, 1920 June 1
    - Harjes to Gee, 1920 June 7
    - Gee to Atkins, 1920 June 9
    - Gee to Morgan, Harjes and Co., 1920 June 9
    - Morgan, Harjes and Co. to Gee, 1920 June 14
    - Mills to Oliver, 1920 June 21
  - Cables
    - Mills to Licross, 1920 July 1
    - Mills to Lewis, 1920 July 1
  - Letters
    - Mills to Roberts, 1920 July 3
    - Mills to Lewis, 1920 July 3
    - Atkins to Mills, 1920 July 5 (Regarding original funding of LORCS by ARC)
    - Mills to Lewis, 1920 July 7
  - Memorandum - Mills to Olds, 1920 July 7
  - Cable - Mills to Lewis, 1920 July 7
  - Letters
    - Lewis to Mills, 1921 February 1
    - Lowrence to Mills, 1921 April 11
    - Brown to Mills, 1921 April 29 (ARC expenditures on behalf of LORCS)
    - Mills to Roberts, 1921 May 11
    - Atkins to Mills, 1921 May 13
    - Lewis to Mills, 1921 August 24
  - Memoranda
    - Mills to Bicknell, 1921 September 8 ("Assisting relief operation of League of Red Cross Societies in Poland". Appropriation WO-40)
    - Simons to Bicknell, 1921 September 14
  - Letter - Mills to Lewis, 1921 September 16
  - Memoranda
    - Simons to Bicknell, 1921 September 17
    - Mills to Simons, 1921 September 19
    - Mills to Bicknell, 1921 September 21 (Appropriations made by Washington for the LORCS)
    - Bicknell to Mills, 1921 September 26
    - Richardson to Mills, 1921 September 26 (Appropriation for Poland, LORCS)
    - Mills to Richardson, 1921 September 28 (same)
    - Mills to Anderson, 1921 October 19
    - Mills to Richardson, 1921 October 19 ("Child Health Fund" appropriation)
  - Letters
    - Mills to Ryan, 1921 October 21
    - Mills to Pratt, 1921 October 21
  - Memoranda
    - Mills to Richardson, 1921 October 25
    - Mills to Bicknell, 1921 October 27 (Latvian scholarship)
    - Mills to Workman, 1921 October 28 (same)
    - Bicknell to Mills, 1921 November 4
  - Cables
    - Burnham to AMCROSS, 1921 November 15
    - Swift to AMCROSS, 1921 November 15
    - Bicknell to Hill, 1921 November 16
  - Letter - Mills to A. R. Hill, 1921 November 17
  - Cable - Payne to Bicknell, 1921 November 25
  - Letters
    - Mills to Simons, 1921 December 1 (Appropriation WO-40. Assisting relief operation of LORCS in Poland)
    - Mills to LORCS, 1922 March 22 (Clarke's expense account)
- Financial statements (Folder 15)
  - Financial statement of the Committee of Red Cross Societies at the Cannes Headquarters for the period from inauguration to 1919 April 30. With memorandum from Seidemann to Rockwell on the finances of LORCS dated 1919 May 14
  - Statement of payments made on account. Committee of Red Cross Societies
  - Personal Ledger. LORCS Statement showing Charges to date in April Account, 1921 April
- Fitzgerald, Alice, Director, Department of Nursing (Folder 16)
  - Letters
    - Fitzgerald, 1919 October 17 (Pages 4, 5, and 6 of a letter signed by A. Fitzgerald re Polish relief work)
    - Fitzgerald to Olds, 1920 March 29
    - Olds to Fitzgerald, 1920 April 21
    - Fitzgerald to Olds, 1920 April 23 (New duties in Paris in connection with the ARC)
- General Council (Folder 17)
  - 1920 March 1 - LORCS. Resolutions submitted for discussion in the Section on Organization at the Meeting of the General Council
- Health Instruction Program for Baltic States (Folder 18)
  - Memorandum, Balfour to Knox, 1921 November 11 (Report on a popular health instruction program for the Baltic States)
- Hill, Claude, Sir, Director General (Folder 19)
  - Letters
    - Emerson to Hill, 1921 June 10 (Child welfare work. To be linked with the national R. C. societies)
    - Hill to Emerson, 1921 June 16
    - Bicknell to Hill, 1922 April 27
    - Bicknell to Hill, 1922 June 16
    - Knox to Hill, 1922 July 6 (Proposal of "central bureau for the exchange of information from the various fields of activity in which the American Red Cross has been interested and from which, at the present time, all of our American personnel has been withdrawn")
- Hoover, Herbert (Folder 20)
  - Letters
    - Persons to Olds, 1919 July 24 (Feeding of children in the liberated countries in reference to Herbert Hoover's connection with ARC)
    - Olds to Persons, 1919 August 4
- International Red Cross, Cooperation with (Folder 21)
  - Letters
    - Keppel to Rappard, 1919 November 12 (Sir David Henderson's suggestion of using the "International Red Cross as an agency for looking up individuals in enemy countries and possibly forwarding sums of money and small packages")
    - Keppel to Rappard, 1919 December 13
    - de Bisping to Rappard, 1920 February 7
    - Rappard to Olds, 1920 February 25
- League of Nations (Folder 22)
  - Letters
    - Henderson to Olds, 1920 April 22 (Requesting the services of Dr. Kendall Emerson of the ARC for position as medical representative to accompany the League of Nations Mission into Russia)
    - Olds to Farrand, 1920 April 27 (Dr. Kendall Emerson)
    - Olds to Henderson, 1920 April 28 (same)
    - Farrand to Olds, 1920 May 19 (same)
    - Drummond to Henderson, 1920 May 31 (Outcome of LORCS General Council in March 1920: "That upon assurance from the League of nations the food, clothing and transportation will be supplied by Governments, the League of Red Cross Societies shall at once formulate plans for the immediate extension of voluntary relief within the affected districts")
  - Article - "Geneva. Capital of the League of Nations"
- Medical Department. Minutes of meetings, 1920 September-December (Folder 23)
  - September
    - 2
    - 9
    - 16
    - 23
    - 30
  - October
    - 7
    - 14
    - 22
    - 28
  - November
    - 4
    - 11
    - 18
    - 27
  - December
    - 2
    - 9
    - 16
    - 23
- Miscellaneous (Folder 24)
  - Letters
    - Drummond to Henderson, 1920 May 31 ("That upon assurance from the League of Nations food, clothing and transportation will be supplied by Governments, the League of red Cross Societies shall at once formulate plans for the immediate extension of voluntary relief within the affected districts." Resolution passed by the General Council in 1920 March)
    - Olds to Henderson, 1920 June 7 (Request for immediate conference in Paris for funding)
  - Cable - Farrand, 1920 November 19
  - Letter - Lakeman to Brown, 1921 April 14 (Possibility of Hungarian Red Cross joining LORCS)
  - Cables
    - Farrand to Pearce, 1921 October 21
    - Farrand to Pearce, 1921 October 21
    - Scot to A. R. Hill, 1922 March 28 (Davison elected Chairman)
  - Map - Countries belonging to the LORCS
  - Memorandum - Fitzgerald (Recommendations concerning moving LORCS headquarters from Geneva to Paris)
- Miscellaneous, 1919 January-July (Folder 25)
  - Letters
    - Persons to Cutler, 1919 May 20 ("... that the League of Red Cross Societies may soon be called upon to deal with a definite proposition from the Supreme Economic Council to undertake a campaign against typhus fever in eastern and southern Europe and to plan for substantial and continuing relief work in that region")
    - Persons to Cutler, 1919 May 21 - Draft of above
  - Memoranda
    - Hunter to Cutler, 1919 May 28
    - Barbour to Olds, 1919 June 3 (Founding of ARC museum and library in Washington)
    - Bicknell to Barbour, 1919 June 5
  - Index, 1919 June 12
  - Cables
    - Farrand to Olds, 1919 June 12 (Eastern European Relief)
    - Henderson to Farrand, 1919 June 14 (same)
    - Henderson to Scheitlin, 1919 June 28 (Appointment of Rappard as Secretary General of the League)
  - Memorandum - Olds to Bobbett, 1919 July 2 (Regarding N. Hapgood, U.S. Minister to Denmark)
  - Cables
    - Davison to Henderson, 1919 July 4 (".....question of policies and relationship between League and individual societies")
- Miscellaneous, 1919 August-October (Folder 26)
  - Cables
    - Ryan, 1919 August 5 (Danish Red Cross)
    - Bicknell to Ryan, 1919 August 6 (With an attached note: proposed conference between Soviet Russian Red Cross and allied Red Cross Societies. Donation to Danish Red Cross)
  - Letter - Persons to Olds, 1919 August 8
  - Cable - Strong to Davison, 1919 August 9
  - Newsclipping - New York Herald, 1919 August 11 ("First Red Cross step to stamp out typhus")
  - Cables
    - Olds to Scheitlin, 1919 August 11 (Typhus situation in Poland)
    - Olds to AMCROSS (Fund drive)
  - Memorandum - Payson to Pres. de la Delegation de Paix, de la Republique d'Azerbaidjan, 1919 August 14
  - Letters
    - Rockwell to Bicknell, 1919 August 19
    - Henderson to Bicknell, 1919 August 19 (Acceptance of contributions from ARC)
    - Bicknell to Henderson, 1919 August 21 (same)
  - Letter - Henderson to Bicknell, 1919 August 21 (Conference minutes re funding)
  - Cables
    - Bicknell to Strong, 1919 August 22
    - Strong, 1919 August 23
    - Farrand to Olds, 1919 August 25 (ARC donation to LORCS)
  - Letter - Bicknell to Rockwell, 1919 August 25
  - Cables
    - Bicknell to LICROSS, 1919 August 25
    - Henderson to Davison, 1919 September 3 (Polish relief work)
  - Letter - Henderson to Bicknell, 1919 September 3 (Repatriation of enemy prisoners of war from Siberia)
  - Memorandum - ARC, 1919 September 9
  - Letters
    - Bicknell to Persons, 1919 September 20 (Polish Red Cross aid to wounded soldiers)
    - Persons to Bicknell, 1919 September 22
  - Cables
    - LICROSS, 1919 September 22
    - Payson to AMCROSS, 1919 September 26
  - Letter - Bicknell to Persons, 1919 September 29
  - Cable - Butkiewicz to Olds, 1919 October 4
  - Letters
    - Walling to Olds, 1919 October 8 (Relationship of the ARC with LORCS)
    - Bicknell to Persons, 1919 October 11
  - Cables
    - Bridges to Wells, 1919 October 13
    - Fitzgerald to AMCROSS, 1919 October 14 (Acceptance of Chief Nurse position for LORCS)
  - Letters
    - Strong to Bicknell, 1919 October 14
    - Persons to Bicknell, 1919 October 17
    - Persons to Bicknell, 1919 October 17
  - Memorandum - Wells to Bicknell, 1919 October 25 (McKee's appointment as Paris representative of LORCS)
- Miscellaneous, 1919 November-December (Box 2., Folder 27)
  - Letters
    - Persons to Chesley, 1919 November 3 (Polish relief work)
    - Bicknell to Rappard, 1919 November 5 (Vienna Committee)
  - Memorandum - Cooke-Smith to Payson, 1919 November 5 (Drugs for the Czecho-Slovak government)
  - Cable - Olds to Bicknell, 1919 November 5 (AMCROSS position in League work in Poland)
  - Letters
    - Cooke-Smith to Persons, 1919 November 5 (Drugs for Czecho-Slovak government)
    - Persons to Allen, 1919 November 6
    - Persons to Bobbett, 1919 November 7
    - Bicknell to Strong, 1919 November 7
    - Persons to Bicknell, 1919 November 27
    - Strong to Bicknell, 1919 November 28
    - Rappard to Bicknell, 1919 November 28
    - Keppel to Bicknell, 1919 November 28 (Relationship of ARC to LORCS)
    - Persons to Payson, 1919 November 29
    - Bicknell to Persons, 1919 November 29
  - Press release-1919 November 30 (Statement issued by Sir David Henderson on the threat of westward extension of typhus from Poland.) Information on the formation of the LORCS and the relations and effects on national Red Cross societies)
  - Letters
    - Fitzgerald to Olds, 1919 December 1